

## **NIDHI SINHA**

3rd Year B-tech Computer Science Student

## **PERSONAL INFO**

8579088290

nidhisinha288@gmail.com

**(ii)** 

linkedin.com/in/nidhi-sinha01

https://github.com/nidhi433

## **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

- Python & MySQL
- Data Visualization using Power BI & Tableau
- Data Analysis in MS Excel
- Web Scrapping in Python
- Web Development in HTML, CSS & PHP
- Web Automation using selenium
- Al and Machine Learning
- Probability & Statistics

## **CHARACTERISTICAL SKILLS**

- -Motivated, well-disciplined individual
- -Works constructively with the tea
- -Can lead team to achieve goals
- -Effective Motivator and Negotiator
- -Communicate Effectively

### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

### Web Development Intern

The Sparks Foundation | June 2021 - July 2021

- Contributed with the lead to create a web-based banking app.
- Used HTML, CSS & Javascript for making the website.

#### **Campus Ambassador**

MyCaptain's | April 2021-May 2021

**Volunteering Internship** 

Youth Empowerment Foundation | May 2021 - June 2021

### Strata Analytica

Student Volunteer | May 2022 - Present

Strata is a startup with a mission to improve and manage infrastructure needs of cities and town around the world

## **SUMMARY**

I'm currently an undergraduate student pursuing a bachelor degree in B-Tech computer science with a specialization in AIML Artificial Intelligence machine learning. I'm looking forward to an opportunity to start my career as machine learning engineer along with a web developer in a company. I'm really passionate about implementing new projects which provide me with challenges and opportunities to improve my skills.

# EDUCATION D Y PATIL INTERNATIONAL UNIVERSITY

B-techCSE - Specialization in AIML | Aug 2019-July 2023

### **SHIVAM CONVENT**

Intermediate in PCM | 67.8%

## HOLY FAITH INTERNATIONAL PUBLIC SCHOOL

Matriculation in Science & Maths | 8.4 CGPA

## **PROJECTS**

### **Neuroscience Data Analysis**

DYPIU | Jun 2021 - Jul 2021

- Studied real-world dataset of Parkinson's Disease
- Performed data visualization & regression

### Car Price Prediction App (08/2021 - 11/2020)

- Performed data preprocessing, data cleaning, data analysis on an existing dataset.
- XGboost was used to build the model, and Streamlit was used to create the web application.

### **Diabetes Predicting**

DYPIU I Nov 2021 - Dec 2021

- Performed EDA on the given dataset
- Used keras for sequential modeling & training the data
- And evaluated the model using the Confusion matrix and ROC curve

## **Covid-19 management system**

DYPIU | Feb 2021 - April 2021

This project is intended to be used as a tool to gather information about the patients who are vaccinated and those who are yet to get vaccine.